Finding Aid for the Fugitive and Agrarian Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Fugitive and Agrarian Collection
2009/2010
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0160
1.68 linear feet
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains 1.67 linear feet of materials on the Fugitive Poets and the Nashville Agrarians. Most of the materials have to do with the years in the 1920’s when the Fugitive poet group was formed and the resulting poems, manuscripts, and correspondence. In addition there are a few items, mostly articles that concern the Agrarian group. The Collection contains many items of unique interest including poems that were read at the Fugitive meetings and correspondence that records the national and international interest in the Fugitive Magazine as it was published in the years 1922 - 1925.
- Fugitive Correspondence - Outgoing
  - Outgoing - April 2, 1923; June 14, 1923; June 21, 1923; June 22, 1923; one undated. Four letters; three typed carbon copies, one original (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Fugitive Correspondence - Incoming
  - Andrews, George Lawrence (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ashurst, John (Box 1)
  - Associated Retailers of Nashville (Box 1)
  - Auslander, Joseph (4) (Box 1)
  - P. Billings Library (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - J. Back Agency (Box 1)
  - Board of Editors of The Fugitive (Box 1)
  - Bartlett, William Allen (Mrs.) (2) (Box 1)
  - Bellaman, Henry (Box 1)
  - Bouterg, M. (2) (Box 1)
  - Boston Public Library (Box 1)
  - Brown University (2) (Box 1)
  - Carmichael, R.D. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - E. H. Clarke and Bro. (Box 1)
  - Cleveland Public Library (3) (Box 1)
  - Comings, A.G. and Son (Box 1)
  - Library of Congress (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cossitt Library (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Craig, John L. (Box 1)
  - Crowell, Norman (Box 1)
  - Cullens, F. B. (Box 1)
  - Dargan, Olive Tilford (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dabbs, James McB. (Box 1)
  - Dillon, George (Box 1)
  - District of Columbia Public Library (Box 1)
  - Don-Carloz, Louisa Cooke (Box 1)
  - Double Dealer (Box 1)
  - Drought, Eugene (Mrs.) (Box 1)
  - Eagle, M.E. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Edmunds, Murrell (Box 1)
  - Elliott, Bill (2) (Box 1)
  - Faxon, F.W. Co. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Field, Ben (3) (Box 1)
  - Florida State College for Women (Box 1)
  - Four Seas Company (Box 1)
  - Franklin Square Agency (Box 1)
  - Gerbaulet, Joy (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Gilbert, Warren (Box 1)
  - Gline, Ellen (Mrs. Walter Ashley) (Box 1)
  - Guyol, Louise P. (Box 1)
  - Harrid (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Harris, Cora Annette (Box 1)
  - Hibbard, C.A. (Box 1)
  - Heizer, Mrs. O.F. (Box 1)
  - Henderson, Rose (Box 1)
  - Jones, Ellen H. (Mrs. W. Palmer) (Box 1)
  - Jones, Mrs. Rosa Weiss (Box 1)
  - King, Sterling P. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lawson McGhee Library (Box 1)
  - Leigh, Ruth (Box 1)
  - Library Association of Portland, Oregon (Box 1)
  - Linnell, John (Box 1)
  - Little, Ronald E. (Box 1)
  - Los Angeles Public Library (Box 1)
  - MacLean, Katharine Allison (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - McClellan, Walter (Box 1)
  - McClurg, A.C. and Company (Box 1)
  - McColl, Katherine Newton (Mrs. Kenneth) (Box 1)
  - Maddock, C. Burnham (Box 1)
  - The Malteaser Magazine (Box 1)
  - Martin, H. F. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Martin, Ruth (Box 1)
  - Merrill, Teresa H. (Box 1)
  - Metcalp, Irving W. (Box 1)
  - Mullins, Helene (Box 1)
  - Munson, Gorham B. (Box 1)
  - Northwestern University (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - New York Public Library (Box 1)
  - Library of the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill (Box 1)
  - North Carolina College for Women (Box 1)
  - “Oldtimer” (Box 1)
  - Payne, T. H. Co. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Peck, Samuel Minton (Box 1)
  - Pendleton, Charles S. (Box 1)
  - University of Pennsylvania (Box 1)
  - Percy, W.A. (William Alexander) (Box 1)
  - Phelps, Wm Lyon (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Pillsbury, Elinor M. (Box 1)
  - Poetry, a Magazine of Verse (Box 1)
  - Poetry Society (Box 1)
  - Public Documents (Gov.t. Printing Office) (Box 1)
  - Porter, F. Wm (Box 1)
  - Post Office Department (Box 1)
  - Potamkin, Harry Allen (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Price, Wm (Box 1)
  - Probst, Leetha J. (Box 1)
  - Purnell, Idella (Box 1)
  - Palms - Poems (Box 1)
  - Quirk, Charles J. (Box 1)
  - Rankin, Louis D. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ranso, John C. (Box 1)
  - Rittenhouse, Jessie (Box 1)
  - Rodgers, Bessie Steger (Mrs.) (Box 1)
  - Savannah Public Library (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Schuchhardt, Edmund C. (Box 1)
  - Seniors Book and Magazine Agency (Box 1)
  - Shaw, A. M., Jr. (Box 1)
  - Shipley, Joseph T. (Box 1)
  - Skavlan, Margaret S. (Box 1)
  - Snell, Ada L. F. (Box 1)
  - Speas, M. H. (Box 1)
  - Spencer, W. (Box 1)
  - Stemheim, M. (Box 1)
  - Stevenson, Burton e. (Box 1)
  - Strong, L.A. G. (Box 1)
  - Tate, Allen (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Taylor, A.R. and Co. (Box 1)
  - The Tennessean (Box 1)
  - Thomas, Ruth (Box 1)
  - Tuttle, B. (Box 1)
  - Untermeyer, Louis (Box 1)
  - Wade, Frank (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Waller, William (Box 1)
  - Wanamaker, John (Box 1)
  - The Wanderer, a Magazine of Poetry (Box 1)
  - The Wave (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Wells, Sabrina Elliott (Box 1)
  - Wight, Hilliard (Box 1)
  - Williams, Mrs. Olin (Box 1)
  - Wilson, John F. (Box 1)
  - World Tomorrow (Box 1)
  - Woodward and Lothrop (Box 1)
  - Wray, J.E. (Box 1)
  - Zdanowitz, Casimir D. (Box 1)
- Fugitive Correspondence - Individual Poets
  - Tate, Allen, 1924 - 1961 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Tate, Allen, 1964 - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Tate, Allen, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Tate, Allen, 1975 - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Warren, Robert Penn, 1925 - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Warren, Robert Penn, 1973 - 1975 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Warren, Robert Penn with publishers, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Warren, Robert Penn to William Humphrey, 1956 - 1967 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Warren, Robert Penn - TLS to Mr. Lohner, June 16, 1957 (certificate of authenticity, gift of Jon Peede) (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Fugitive Correspondence - other
  - Incoming subscription orders - 18 order cards (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Incoming announcements (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Papers relating to The Fugitive Magazine and group
  - Mailing lists - members of Poetry Society of Texas; subscription list; list of reviewers, critics, complimentary copies (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Mailing lists - list of reviewers; subscription list; complimentary copies; subscribers who have not renewed (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Mailing lists - lists of patrons; bookshops; members in Dallas; rejections; W. Clyde Curry’s subscription list (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Subscription announcement – Poetry Guild of Nashville, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Business papers - bills, vouchers, invoices, etc. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Business papers - bills, vouchers, invoices, etc. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Business papers - invoices, mailing memoranda (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Business papers - reports, memoranda, proposals (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minutes from the November 5, 1924 meeting (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous papers (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Fugitive - Table of Contents, Mastheads (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Fugitive - Partial MS of February - March 1923 issue as it went to the printer; ten poems with table of contents and editorial page (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The Fugitive - photograph of advertisement for Vol. 1, no. 4, December 1922 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Fugitive Anthology Papers - Foreword and history of the Fugitive Group (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Poems read at Fugitive Meetings
  - Moore, Merrill (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Ransom, John Crowe (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Stevenson, Alec Brock (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Tate, Allen (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Warren, Robert Penn (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Wills, Jesse (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Frank, James M. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hirsch, Sidney M. (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Stanley (Box 2)
  - Wills, Ridley (Box 2)
- Other poems read at the meetings
  - Authors not given (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Authors not given (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Authors not given (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Authors not given (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Authors not given (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Authors not given (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Other poems by the Fugitives
  - Curry, Walter Clyde (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Davidson, Donald (Box 2)
  - Frierson, William (Box 2)
  - Frank, James M. (Box 2)
  - Gottschalk, Laura Riding (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Stanley (Box 2)
  - Moore, Merrill (Box 2)
  - Stevenson, Alec Brock (Box 2)
  - Tate, Allen (Box 2)
  - Warren, Robert Penn (Box 2)
  - Wills, Ridley (Box 2)
- Poems by contributors to The Fugitive
  - Bynner, Witter (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Fletcher, John Gould (Box 2)
  - Martin, Hermann Ford (Box 2)
  - R.S.W. Jr. (Box 2)
  - L.A.G. Strong (Box 2)
- Fugitive Anthology Papers - Poems
  - Frank, James M. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Johnson, Stanley (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Ransom, John Crowe (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Stevenson, Alec Brock (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Tate, Allen (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Tate, Allen (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Warren, Robert Penn (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Wills, Jesse (Box 2, Folder 33)
- The Fugitive Magazine - Reviews
  - Photocopies of reviews of The Fugitive, 1922 - 1925 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Photocopies of reviews of The Fugitive, February - June 1928 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- 1956 Fugitive Reunion
  - Newspaper and magazine articles (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Newspaper and magazine articles (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Programs for dinner in honor of the Fugitives, May 4, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Programs – Poetry reading in Neely Auditorium at Vanderbilt, May 4, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Poems read at the reunion by Merrill Moore and John Crowe Ransom (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Calendar of Reunion Events; List of those in attendance; dust jacket of book Fugitives’ Reunion: Conversations at Vanderbilt (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Other materials relating to the Fugitives and Agrarians
  - Program - Literary Department of the Centennial Club, February 25, 1926 (Lyle Lanier) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Vanderbilt Literary Symposium - Writing Laboratory Conference - 5 papers by participants taught by Warren Beck, Andrew Lytle, Richard Weaver, Donald Davidson and Walter Sullivan (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Thomas Daniel Young, Professor of English at Vanderbilt (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with Thomas Daniel Young, Professor of English at Vanderbilt (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Fugitive associations - Randall Jarrell - “Generations of Writers Inspired” by Robert Watson in Alumni News, University of North Carolina at Greensboro, Spring 1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper article “50 Candles for the Fugitives” Wednesday, April 19, 1972 and photocopies of other newspaper articles (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Article “Reflections on the Fugitives: Fifty Years and After” with attachment of pages from Understanding Poetry by Cleanth Brooks and Robert Penn Warren (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Programs - Downeast Southern Renascence Conference “A Sense of Place” at the University of Southern Maine, October 29 - 31, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Publication announcements from, 1976, 1977, and 1979 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bibliography “Fugitive/Agrarian Materials at Vanderbilt University” by Martha Emily Cook and Thomas Daniel Young, Vanderbilt University Bibliographic list of Fugitive/Agrarian M.A. and Ph.D. Theses, 1973 - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Materials on individual Fugitives and Agrarians
  - Davidson, Donald - Correspondence, 1906 - 1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Davidson, Donald - Program - “Tradition and Change in Lyric Poetry” Four lectures at Vanderbilt given by Davidson (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Davidson, Donald - Photocopy of a letter from RG 600, Library University Archives, D.D. to Dr. A.F. Kuhlman, May 11, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Davidson, Donald - unpublished manuscript - “The Center That Holds: Southern Literature and the Old Time Religion.” 17 pages, 1966. Footnotes added by T.D. Young in 1968. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Davidson, Donald - Newspaper clippings, obituaries (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Hirsch, Sidney M. - Correspondence – photocopies (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Hirsch, Sidney M. - “Art and Mysticism” and other poems – photocopies (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Hirsch, Sidney M. - newspaper articles - obituary of S.M. Hirsch “Fugitive Poet Founder Dies”; “Nashvillians Espouse Relocation of U.S. Capitol on Mississippi River” - photocopies (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Johnson, Stanley - student paper by Frances Neel Cheney, October 4, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Lytle, Andrew Nelson - An Andrew Nelson Lytle Checklist, 1923 - 1959 by Jack de Bellis, Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, June 1966 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Moore, Merrill - Correspondence to A.F. Kuhlman - Photocopies from RG 600, Library, Vanderbilt University Archives (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Moore, Merrill - Broadside advertisements for Clinical Sonnets and More Clinical Sonnets (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Moore, Merrill - Miscellaneous items: (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Moore, John Trotwood. “Success,” a poem printed on card with brief biography on card, with brief biography on reverse side. 2 copies
    Inscription on How to Know Architecture (title not shown). Frank Edwin Wallis, New
    York and London, 1914. “Herbert Sanborn, January 10, 1923, presented by Merrill Moore.”
    Program - “A Reading and Definition of the Sonnet Form,” by Merrill Moore. Presented under the auspices of the Gertrude Clarke Whittall Poetry Fund. The Coolidge Auditorium, February 2, 1953
    Holograph poem - “... and, to the young man.. .,” autographed, ca. 1925
    Holograph poem - “The Lady of the Lambs” by Alice Meynell, presented to Mrs.
    Adolph Skinner; cover letter from Herschel Gower to Marice Wolfe.
  - Ransom, John Crowe - Correspondence - Outgoing, 1941 - 1942 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Ransom, John Crowe - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Ransom, John Crowe - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Ransom, John Crowe - Title page only “ The South - Old or New?” Reprinted from The Sewanee Review, 1928. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Ransom, John Crowe - extract from a speech by J.C.R. delivered at Richmond, November 14, 1930 in the Barr - Ransom debate on Industrialism vs. Agrarianism (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Ransom, John Crowe - Student papers by Frances Neel Cheney (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Ransom, John Crowe - Student papers by Frances Neel Cheney and Dillard Jacobs (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Ransom, John Crowe - “A Tribute from the Community” edited by D. David Long and Michael R. Burr. Supplement to the Kenyon Collegian, Vol. 90, no. 7, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Ransom, John Crowe - Memorial Service, order of service, November 1, 1974; with Invitation to Brainard and Frances Cheney, October 15, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Ransom, John Crowe - Bibliographies - photocopies of pages concerning J.C.R. from A Bibliographic Guide to the Study of Southern Literature; John Crowe Ransom, 1888 -1974 Photocopies (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Stevenson, Alec Brock - Poem - “In the County of Davidson” typescript (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Stewart, Randall (Fugitive associate) -“The Outlook for Southern Writing: Diagnosis and Prognosis” reprint from Virginia Quarterly Review, Vol. 31, no. 2, Spring 1955. With Inscription “For Frances and Lon Cheney, with all good wishes of Randall Stewart.” (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Tate, Allen - Correspondence - Outgoing and Incoming (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Tate, Allen – Poem - “The Anabasis” Holograph, January 14, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Tate, Allen - Poem - “A Ballade of the Lugubrious Wench” from The Jade, November 12, Vol. 111, no. 1, p. 17 - photocopy (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Tate, Allen – Poem- “Ode to the Confederate Dead” with a translation by Jacques and Raissa Maritain, reprint from The Sewanee Review, Vol. LX, No. 3, Summer 1952 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Tate, Allen - Article - “Dostoevsky’s Hovering Fly” reprinted from the Summer number of The Sewanee Review, 1943. (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Materials on individual Fugitives and Agrarians
  - Tate, Allen - Personnel Assayer; Moral Judgment Test, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Tate, Allen - Southwestern Bulletin - Faculty Register, Vol. 21, no.4, September 1934, Memphis, Tennessee (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Tate, Allen - Article - “Allen Tate as Man of Letters” by Richmond C. Beatty, reprint from The South Atlantic Quarterly, Vol. 47, no. 2, April 1948 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Tate, Allen - “Homage to Allen Tate Essays, Notes, and Verses in Honor of his Sixtieth Birthday” The Sewanee Review, Vol. LXVII, no. 4, Autumn 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Tate, Allen - Elliott Carter’s Score for Emblems with lyrics by Tate. Inscription “To Thank Allen Tate”, February 7, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Tate, Allen - Christmas card, 1967 - original verse (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Tate, Allen - “Rumors of Mortality: An Introduction to Allen Tate” by Melvin E. Bradford In Studies in Southeastern Culture, Vol. 1, no. 1, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Tate, Allen - Article - “Allen Tate: Poet in Residence” in The Sewanee News, December 1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Tate, Allen - Lecture - “Mere Literature and the Lost Traveller” reprint of the Fourth Annual C.C. Williamson Lecture given by Tate at the Peabody Library School, Nashville, Tennessee, July 17, 1969 with program (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Tate, Allen - Poem by Sister Mary Anthony Barr on the occasion of Tate’s receiving of the Aquinas Medal, July 5, 1974 - photocopy (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Tate. Allen - 75th Birthday Celebration items: (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Program “Celebration of the Seventy-Fifth Birthday of Allen Tate Poet - Novelist
    Critic” The University of the South, November 15 - 16, 1974, 3 copies
    Biographies of eight of the participants
    List of participants - photocopy
  - Tate, Allen - 75th Birthday Celebration items: (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Schedule of events
    Press releases from the News Rom, University of the South concerning the event Tennessean article “ Sewanee Event to cite poet, critic Allen Tate” November 11, 1974
    Letter - Jesse Wills to Frank Grisham, November 18, 1974
  - Tate, Allen - Poem - “At Delphi” by William Jay Smith for Allen Tate on his 75th birthday, November 19, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Tate, Allen - Poem “The First Day Out from Troy” by Radcliffe Squires for Allen Tate’s 75th birthday, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Tate, Allen - The Western Approaches, Poems 1973 -75 by Howard Nemerov - Book jacket with note: “Einstein and Freud and Jack: to Allen Tate on his 75th birthday” pp. 20 - 21 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Tate, Allen - Broadsides: (Box 4, Folder 16)
    “All is Brillig (or ought to be)” Palaemon Press, 1978, signed “Allen Tate”, copy No. 5
    “For the Poet.. .” by Allen Tate. Calligraphy by Helen Tate 1979
    “Song from Buffalo” by Leslie A. Fiedler, December 1975, signed by Leslie A.
    Fiedler. Presented “with the compliments of the Director of Libraries”
  - Tate, Allen - The First Year of Greek by James T. Allen. New York: MacMillan Company, 1918. Signature, notes, caricatures of Tate by Andy White. Association copy. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Warren, Robert Penn. Audubon: A Vision - Advance Proofs uncorrected, October 1969, Random House, Inc. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Warren, Robert Penn. Program - Convocation University of the South, October 10, 1974. Honorary doctorate for R.P. Warren ( 2 copies) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Warren, Robert Penn. Notes on an Approach to Literature, Fifth Edition, 1975 by Cleanth Brooks and Robert Penn Warren. Prentice - Hall, Inc. Englewood Cliffs, New Jersey (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Warren, Robert Penn. Promotional brochures: The Ultimate Private Library, Franklin (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Library and American Express Company, March 1974. Warren on the Board of Distinquished scholars.
    First Edition Society by the Franklin Library, 1976 - Warren’s books among those offered by the society
  - Wills, Ridley - Sonnet - “To Rupert Brooke” 1 holograph copy; 2 photocopies (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Wills, Ridley Lanier, Lyle - Vanderbilt University Commencement Program, 1923 (includes their names) (Box 4, Folder 23)
- The Agrarians
  - Davidson, Donald - article - “Where Regionalism and Sectionalism Meet” reprint from Social Forces, Vol. 13, No. 1, October 1934. Inscribed by Davidson. (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Article - “The Agrarian Inheritance: an Affirmation” by Melvin E. Bradford from the Proceedings of the Gulf Coast History and Humanities Conference, IV (1973). Inscribed by author. (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Article - “Donald Davidson and the Tennessee Valley Authority: The Response of a Southern Conservative” by Edward S. Shapiro in Tennessee Historical Quarterly, Winter 1974. (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Article - “The South, the Tradition, and the Traditionalist” by Hunter Kay in Versus, February 1975. (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Articles - “They Took Their Stand” …but were they all wrong? Paper by John Compton Presented February 2, 1978 to the Round Table, Nashville, Tennessee. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    “Science, Anti - Science and Human Values” by John Compton reprint from The Key Reporter, Winter, 1978 - 1979.
  - Lanier, Lyle - Vanderbilt University College on Campus, August 1 - 5, 1979 - recommended reading list, maps, participants, schedule. Faculty includes Lanier. (Box 4, Folder 29)